Jonathan M. Varner

jon.varner@gmail.com

773.559.6208

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jon-varner/

20 years of Web development experience, including all stages of development, from strategy and concepting to UX analysis to implementation to maintenance and reporting. Experience managing a team of front-end developers and working effectively with project managers, account managers, creative directors, designers, and clients.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

closerlook, inc.

Interactive Lead, Manager – 2016-2018 Lead Interactive Developer – 2013-2016 Senior Interactive Developer – 2010-2013 Interactive Developer – 2007-2010

Led development of websites and interactive applications. I have been instrumental in establishing and enhancing closerlook's code base and development process to improve performance, maintainability, and accessibility.

Recent clients include:

Smith & Nephew, Horizon, Novo Nordisk, Astellas, Bioverativ, Takeda

Recent accomplishments include:

- Significant refactoring and enhancements to closerlook's custom website framework, including conversion from Web Forms to ASP.NET MVC; conversion from CSS to SCSS; conversion from ES5 to ES6; standardization of responsive techniques; and creation of modular components (e.g., navigation systems, persistent panels, animations, etc.) to streamline development.
- Development of responsive websites and interactive articles for several pharmaceutical clients. These implemented SVG, CSS, and JavaScript animations to engage healthcare professionals with informational material, while tracking specific user behaviors via JSON exchange with a C#/Entity Framework-based back end.
- Development of a Unity/C#-based game demonstrating the method of action of a pharmaceutical client's product. This included persistent leaderboard functionality to encourage engagement in a playful way.
- Establishing and maintaining the tech team's coding standards and best practices.
- Establishing a peer code review process that encourages a positive exchange of techniques and approaches between fellow developers.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Focus: JavaScript (ES6, React, jQuery, GSAP), HTML5, CSS3 (SCSS), C#, ASP.NET MVC

Experience: SQL Server, Node, Angular, Vue, Unity, Wordpress, Sitecore, Kentico

Sitecore Certified Developer

LEADERSHIP SKILLS

Interviewed, hired and managed Interactive Developers

Built custom career development plans

Attended Manager Tools Effective Manager Conference

EDUCATION

Cedarville College, Bachelor of Arts, English 1994

PERSONAL INTERESTS

history, biking, hiking, board games, guitars and a modular synthesizer

TribeAgency

Web Developer - 2005-2007

Led development of website and interactive applications, including database development. Contributed to strategy and user experience analysis.

Clients included:

National Council of State Boards of Nursing, Holabird & Root, Hilton Hotels, Insuresoft, and United Stationers.

Accomplishments included:

- Development of a series of modular Flash-and-XML-based educational quizzes for the National Council of State Boards of Nursing (NCSBN), as well as a Web-based administrative tool for generating quizzes.
- Development of corporate website for architecture firm Holabird & Root.
- Led the agency's transition from classic ASP to ASP.NET
- Implemented significant improvements in database access code to improve security, maintainability, and performance
- Established agency's coding best practices and a reusable code library

Zipatoni

Web Developer – 1999-2005

Responsible for development and maintenance of website applications, including database development. These included corporate and retail websites, sweepstakes, instant win, ecommerce and postcard applications.

Clients included:

Dreyer's Ice Cream, eBay, Motorola, Verizon, Visa, British Airways

PRIOR PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer, Schwa Digital Design (acquired by Zipatoni) – 1998-1999

SGML Developer, Computer Sciences Corporation – 1997-1998

Systems Administrator, Computer Sciences Corporation – 1996-1997

Technical Editor, Computer Sciences Corporation – 1995-1996